The morning air tasted of desperation and the faint, sweet decay that clung to the root-bound
rind district.
Alby, a Jonathan Apple whose skin bore the honest scuffs of tireless work, pulled his
tattered wagon through the narrow, unpaved lanes.
Each jolt sent a tremor through his core, mirroring the unease churning within him.
His family orchard, a sprawling patchwork of gnarled branches and withered leaves, was
bleeding out.
The blight, it had crept in like a silent viscous tendril, throttling their last harvest,
threatening to pull the very roots from under their ancestral earth.
Hope, a fragile bloom in the face of ruin, now rested on a single precarious thread, a stall
at the grand orchard market.
Not just any stall, but one blessed by the perfect produce-gilled, the gilded gatekeepers
of fruit society.
Without it, the future of the Jonathan's, a lineage once famed for their robust flavor
and resilience would surely rot away.
The market, when Alby finally reached its towering, polished gates, was a world away from
his district's humble dust.
It was a cathedral of crisp, vibrant color, a symphony of hushed, self-important chatter.
Leaming displays of ruby-red cherries, sun-kissed peaches and flawless, emerald pairs stood sentinel,
their surfaces catching the light like precious jewels.
Alby, with his slightly duller sheen and the worry lines etched near his stem, felt every
ounce of his humble origins keenly.
He made his way through the opulent throng, the murmuring crowd parting around him as
if his presence were an unseemly bruise on their pristine canvas.
The gilded offices were at the market's heart, a circular pavilion of dark, polished wood
and shimmering glass, taking a deep, fortifying breath that tasted of anxiety and faint apple
wood, Alby pushed open the heavy ornate door.
Inside, the air was cool, sterile and faintly perfumed with the scent of expensive wax.
And a vast mahogany desk sat Madame Gala.
She was, as her name suggested, a gala apple of breathtaking, almost intimidating perfection.
Her skin gleamed with an unnatural polish, a deep, unblemished blush fading seamlessly
into a creamy yellow.
Not a single blemish, not a hint of a bruise, marred her impeccable form.
Her stem, a slender, dark green, was perfectly upright, and her leaf, though small, was
a vibrant, uncurled flag of superiority.
Her eyes, sharp and dark as polished seeds, surveyed Alby with a gaze that stripped him
bare, assessing his flaws with a chilling efficiency.
Ah, Alby Jonathan, she purred, her voice a low melodic hum that somehow graded on his
nerves.
We've been expecting you, your application, rather rustic, wouldn't you say?
Her gaze flickered to the faint scuffs on his skin, a silent judgment.
Alby straightened his posture, trying to inject some defiance into his tired frame.
My family's been working this land for generations, Madame Gala, our roots run deep.
We have a heritage of quality, even if the recent blight.
The blight, she interrupted, a faint, almost imperceptible curl of her perfectly sculpted
lip.
Yes, we've heard about the challenges in the root bound-rind, unfortunate, so much good
fruit gone to waste or worse spreading their affliction.
Her words were delivered with a cold, almost surgical precision, each one a tiny barbe.
We need that stall, Madame Gala, Alby pressed, his voice tight with an urgency he couldn't
hide, to keep our family afloat to save our orchard.
Madame Gala leaned back, her flawless surface catching the overhead light, a slow, chilling
smile unfurled on her face, the kind that promised something dreadful.
A stall in the grand orchard market is not a handout, Alby.
It's a privilege, a testament to excellence, to purity, and the guild, as you know, maintains
the strictest standards.
She paused, letting the silence stretch, thick with unspoken demands, Alby's core tightened.
She knew what was coming.
The perfect produce guild was notorious for its tests, its gatekeeping rituals that
often involved more moral compromise than agricultural acumen.
There's a matter, Alby, Madame Gala continued, her voice dropping to a conspiratorial whisper,
yet still echoing with an unnerving clarity in the quiet office.
A small, situation that has come to our attention, concerning Barnaby Bramley.
Barnaby felt a cold, not form in his pulp.
Barnaby, his friend, his neighbor.
A sturdy, reliable Bramley apple, his rough skin often bruised from honest toil, his heart
as good as gold.
They had shared harvests, commiserated over bad seasons, and even exchanged the occasional
barrel of cider.
Barnaby, Alby managed his voice a strained croak.
Yes, it seems, a rumor has surfaced, a whisper really among the more discerning of our
purveyors.
About a possible blight, a very aggressive strain potentially infecting his own crops.
Madame Gala's eyes narrowed, pinning Alby, a blight that could, if not contained, spread
far beyond the root-bound-rind, a blight that could, contaminate the very produce of
this market.
Alby felt a surge of ice-cold dread.
That's impossible, Barnaby's orchard is clean.
As meticulous, he wouldn't let anything like that happen.
Ah, but that's where you come in, Alby, Madame Gala said, her smile widening into a predatory
grin.
We need a statement from someone within the root-bound-rind, someone respected, someone who has intimate knowledge
of the local conditions, a public denunciation, a confirmation of Barnaby's supposed affliction.
Just a word a little nod that his crops are indeed, compromised for the greater good you
understand, to protect the integrity of the market, and of course to secure your family's
future with that coveted stall.
The air in the office suddenly felt thick suffocating.
Alby's blood ran cold then hot with outrage, betray Barnaby, his friend.
Acuse him of blight of spreading ruin when he knew it was a lie, the words tasted like
ash in his mouth.
You want me to lie, Alby's voice was barely a whisper yet it trembled with incredulity.
Madame Gala chuckled, a dry, rustling sound like withered leaves.
Oh, Alby, let's not be so dramatic, it's a pragmatic decision, a necessary measure.
Think of it as a small, unavoidable sacrifice for the greater good, for your family, for
your legacy.
Let his one-bramley's reputation when set against the survival of an entire Jonathan
lineage, Alby's mind reeled.
He saw his family's faces, his stoic father, his tired mother, his younger siblings whose
small cores ached with hunger.
He saw there orchard, the skeletal trees standing like silent sentinels waiting for a miracle.
And then he saw Barnaby, his rough, honest face, his booming laugh, the shared history of
resilience and hardship.
Barnaby, who would give you the very core from his chest if you needed it.
The moral calculus was a torment.
Families future, a desperate, tangible need weighed against the crushing betrayal of a
true friend.
His principles hammered into him by generations of honest, hardworking apples, screamed in protest.
How could he look at himself at the bruise that would forever mark his own core if he
did this?
But a stall, one through such deceit, ever truly taste sweet.
I, I can't, Alby choked out his voice raw, the words tore from his chest, painful and
absolute.
I can't do it, Barnaby, he's innocent.
His orchard is sound, I won't lie about him, not for a thousand stalls.
Madame Gailas perfect smile didn't falter, but a chilling glint entered her dark eyes.
Oh, Alby, such integrity, such sentimentality, it's almost quaint.
She leaned forward, her voice dropping to a level that was no longer conspiratorial, but
utterly devoid of warmth.
You truly believe this was a choice, don't you?
A sickening dread coiled in Alby's stomach.
What do you mean?
Madame Gaila let out a soft, almost pitting sigh.
The blight, Alby, it wasn't the real problem, not for us, and Barnaby Bramley, a convenient
distraction, a way to gauge your character.
We have so many ways of determining the true quality of a fruit beyond mere surface appearance.
She reached beneath her desk, her movements languid, deliberate.
Alby watched frozen as her perfectly manicured hand emerged holding a small, intricately
carved wooden box.
It was old, worn smooth by generations of handling.
Alby's breath hitched.
This box, Madame Gaila said, her voice dripping with triumphant satisfaction holds the key
to true quality.
The seeds of the legendary crimson heart, Jonathan.
Your family's heirloom seeds, the ones your ancestor, Old Man Jonathan, brought across
the great divide, the ones that produce fruit with unparalleled sweetness and an unusual
resistance to rot.
Alby felt his knees buckle, his family's heirloom seeds.
The very essence of their lineage, safeguarded for centuries, whispered about in hushed,
reverent tones.
How?
How did you get those?
Alby stammered, his mind a frantic, desperate scramble for an answer he already knew.
Madame Gaila's eyes sparkled with malicious amusement.
Your uncle bless his well-meaning but utterly misguided core.
He was so keen to help your struggling family.
Said he was desperate to secure some market assistance for you.
He presented them to us weeks ago as a goodwill gesture, a token of future collaboration,
hoping it would guarantee your family a spot.
Said they were a priceless family secret, but he was willing to invest them for your
sake.
She tapped the wooden box with a perfectly polished nail.
He called it a calculated risk, we called it, an acquisition.
The words hit Alby like a sudden brutal blow to his core, his uncle, kind but always
a little too eager, too easily swayed.
He hadn't just hoped for market assistance.
He'd sold off the family's most sacred treasure, the very bedrock of their identity for
a gamble.
He thought he was helping you, Alby.
Madame Gaila continued, a cruel smile playing on her lips.
He truly did.
A touching display of familial loyalty wouldn't you say, and utterly naive.
The seeds Alby were the true prize, the stall, a mere formality, a crumb tossed to the
loyal.
She pushed a crisp, official looking document across the desk.
Consider this your contract, Alby Jonathan.
A stall as requested for your struggling family, a token of the perfect produce guilds,
benevolence, your integrity as you put it remains intact.
You didn't betray your friend, you simply arrived too late to stop the real betrayal,
and you never even knew it was happening under your own vine.
Alby stared at the contract, then at the wooden box clutched in Madame Gaila's hand.
The word swam before his eyes.
He had stood firm, he had held his ground, he had refused to compromise his principles,
and for what?
To discover that the battle had been lost weeks ago by his own kin in a desperate, foolish
act of love.
He had won the stall, yes, a hollow victory that felt like a mockery.
His integrity, though unbruised by his own actions, had been weaponized against him, a mere
prop in Madame Gaila's cold, calculating game.
He felt the bitter taste of helplessness rise in his throat, a raw, burning sensation that
stung more than any physical blight.
The weight of a bruised heart, indeed, not from his own compromise, but from a revelation
that tore at the very roots of his family, exposing a hidden truth far more painful than
any blight on his trees.
He had saved Barnaby, but at what cost?
His family's most precious legacy was gone, swallowed by the polished, unfeeling more
of the grand orchard market, leaving Alby to face the devastating reality.
He was a Jonathan Apple with his core exposed, his inheritance stolen, and a profound, aching
betrayal, large deep within his pulp.